In this video, we're going to introduce another important concept in bottom-up
在这段视频中，我们将介绍自下而上的另一个重要概念
parsing, the notion of a handle. To review, bottom up parsing is these two
解析，句柄的概念。回顾一下，自下而上的解析是这两个
kinds of actions: we have shift moves, which just read one token of input and
动作种类：我们有Shift Moves，它只读取一个输入标记，
move the vertical bar one to the right, And reduced moves, which replace the right
将竖条向右移动一个，并减少移动，以替换右侧
hand side of a production [inaudible] to the left of the vertical bar by a
产品的手边[听不见]在竖条的左边
production left hand side. So in this case, the production must have been A goes
制作左手边。所以在这种情况下，生产一定是A级的
to XY. And also reviewing what we did in the last video, the left string can be
致XY。再回顾一下我们在上一个视频中所做的，左边的字符串可以是
implemented by a stack, where the top of the stack is marked by the vertical bar.
由堆栈实现，其中堆栈的顶部由竖线标记。
So shift pushes the terminal on to the stack and reduce pops zero or more symbols
因此，Shift会将终端推到堆栈上，并减少POP零个或多个符号
of the stack, and that's gonna be the right hand stack of some production. And
在堆栈中，这将是一些产品的右边堆栈。和
then it's going to push one non-terminal on to the stack which is the left hand
然后，它将把一个非终端推到堆栈上，也就是左手
side of that same production. And the key question in bottom of parsing and the one
同一部作品的另一面。而句法分析底层的关键问题是
we haven't addressed at all yet is how do we decide when to shift and when to
我们还没有解决的问题是，我们如何决定何时转移和何时转移
reduce. So let's take a look at this example grammar. And let's think about a
减少。让我们看一下这个示例语法。让我们想一想一个
step of a parse where we've shifted one token onto the stack. We have Nth on the
解析的一步，我们将一个令牌移到堆栈上。我们有第N个在
stack, and then we have times N plus N still to go that we haven't seen yet. Now
堆栈，然后我们还有N乘以N+N，我们还没有看到。现在
at this point we could decide to reduce by T goes to N because we have the production
在这一点上，我们可以决定将T减去N，因为我们有
T goes to Nth right here. And so we could then get into this particul-, potential
T去第N个，就在这里。这样我们就可以进入这个粒子势能
state, or this particular state, where we have T on the stack and then the rest of
状态，或者这个特定的状态，其中堆栈上有T，然后是的睡觉
the input that looks like that. A-, but you can see that this would be a mistake.
看起来像那样的输入。A-，但是你可以看到这将是一个错误。
There is no production in the grammar that begins Hence T times. There's no
因此T次开始的语法中没有产生式。没有
production up here that looks like T times. And therefore if we were to, to, to
这里的生产量看起来是T倍。所以如果我们要，要
make this move, we would get stuck. We could continue to do reductions, to
走这一步，我们会被卡住的。我们可以继续减少，
rummage around in the string. But we would never be able to get back to the start
在绳子上翻找。但是我们再也不能回到起点了
symbol. Because there is no way to deal a sub string that has t times something in
符号。因为没有办法处理t乘以某项的子字符串。
it. So what that shows us is that we don't always want to reduce just because we have
它。这向我们表明，我们并不总是想要减少，因为我们拥有
the right-hand side of a production on top of the stack. To repeat that, even if
作品的右手边，在堆叠的顶部。再重复一遍，即使
there's the right-hand side of some production sitting right there on top of
有一些作品的右手边就在那里
the stack, it might be a mistake to do a reduction. We might want to wait and do
堆栈，进行缩减可能是错误的。我们可能要等一等再做
our reduction someplace else. And the idea about how we decide is that we only want
我们在别的地方减价。关于我们如何决定的想法是，我们只想
to reduce if the result can still be reduced to the start symbol. So let's take
如果结果仍然可以减少到开始符号，则设置为减去。所以让我们带上
a look at a right most innervations. So, beginning with the start symbol, we get to
看看最右侧的神经。所以，从开始符号开始，我们就可以
some state after, after some number of steps where that means, just an arbitrary
一些状态之后，在一些步骤之后，这意味着，只是一个任意的
number of steps. We get to some state X is the right most non-terminal and then the
步骤数。我们得到某种状态X是最右边的非终结点，然后
next step is to replace X with by the right hand side of some production. And
下一步是将X替换为某些产品的右侧。和
remember, again, with bottom up parsing, the parsers are actually going in this
请再次记住，对于自下而上的解析，解析器实际上是这样做的
direction, okay. So, this is the reduction direction. The derivation direction, the
方向，好的。所以，这就是减少的方向。派生方向、派生方向
production direction, Because that's the easiest way to talk about what strings are
生产方向，因为这是谈论字符串是什么的最简单的方式
derived. We wanna begin with a start symbol. But the [inaudible], but the
派生的。我们想从一个开始符号开始。但是[听不见]，但是
parser's actually going against the flow of these arrows. Anyway if this is a
解析器实际上与这些箭头的流向背道而驰。不管怎样，如果这是一个
rightmost derivation Then we say that alpha beta is a handle of alpha beta
最右边的派生，我们说αβ是αβ的句柄
omega. And that just means that, yes, it would be okay in this situation to reduce
欧米茄。这就意味着，是的，在这种情况下，减少
beta to X. And we could replace beta by X, because it's not a mistake. We can still,
从β到X，我们可以用X代替β，因为这不是一个错误。我们仍然可以，
by some sequence of moves, get back to the start symbol. You know, by, by doing more
通过一系列的动作，回到开始符号。你知道，通过，通过做更多
reductions. So handles formulize the intuition about where it is okay to do a
减价。因此句柄公式化了关于在哪里可以做
reduction. A handle is just a reduction that also allows further reduction back to
减少。句柄只是一个折减，它还允许进一步折回到
the start symbol And we clearly only want to do reduction at handles. If we do a
开始符号，我们显然只想在句柄上做减法。如果我们做一个
reduction at a place that is not a handle even though it looks like it's the right
在一个不是手柄的地方减少，即使它看起来是正确的
hand side or maybe actually be the right hand side of some production, that does
或者可能实际上是某些产品的右手边，这样做是正确的
not mean. That it's actually a handle, and we might, if we could reduce there, we may
不刻薄。它实际上是一个把手，我们可能，如果我们可以在那里减少，我们可能会
get stuck. So all we said so far is what a handle is. We've defined, a handle, We
被卡住了。到目前为止，我们所说的就是句柄是什么。我们已经定义了，一个句柄，我们
haven't said anything about how to find the handles. And actually, how we find the
我还没说怎么找到把手呢。实际上，我们是如何找到
handles is gonna consume much of the rest of our discussion of parsing.
句柄将占用我们讨论的解析的大部分睡觉内容。